Resume

http://coderbear.com/resume.pdf Seeking a Summer Internship for 2017

Siddharth Anil Bhagwan siddharthabhagwan@gmail.com +1-(240)-917-9505

Over 6 years of experience as a web developer and experience designer around products and services. Currently pursuing my masters in HCI, while transitioning into Data Visualization and Big Data.

Education

MS Human Computer Interaction, University of Maryland, Aug 2016 - May 2018 GPA 4.0 B.Tech Information Technology, PEC University of Technology, India, 2006 - 2010

Skills

Analytics - R Studio | Tableau | Jigsaw | Google Analytics

Design - InVision | Prototyping | Personas | Storyboarding | Wireframing | Balsamiq | Photoshop

Languages - JavaScript | Ruby | HTML | CSS | Shell Scripting | XSLT | Java

Libs, Frameworks & Db - React | Rails | Bootstrap | jQuery | Skrollr | Arduino | Postgresql

Tools & Protocols - Git | REST | SOAP | Grunt | Eclipse | WebSphere MB, MQ, DataPower

OS & Utilities - Mac OS | Unix | Windows | Travis CI | Heroku | AWS

Work Experience

MS Human Computer Interaction, University of Maryland | Aug 2016 - May 2018 | College Park

Data Science - Using US DoE data to identify and predict admissions patterns

Analytics - Quantifying self efficacy in seeking health related information online in US for major races

CyberPsychology - Noticeability and impact of visual queues on USB 2.0 connectors

Design Methodologies - Redesigning the coach experience in flights for sleepers

DevToProd & Codemancers, Freelance Front End Engineer | Sep 2015 - April 2016 | Remote Design, development and performance benchmarking of front end modules using JavaScript.

Revealing Hour Creations, Software Engineer & Experience Designer | April 2014 - May 2015 | Pune, India 8 member hardware & software startup. Tah | Piano Stairs | Laser Harp | Doo | The Incarnate Word.

Lectito, Full Stack Web Developer | Mar 2013 - Mar 2014 | Remote Complete design and development of Lectito, a platform to exchange books. Project dormant.

IBM, Systems Engineer for Enterprise Integration | Aug 2010 - Feb 2013 | Pune, India Middleware Engineer in EAI for Vodafone India. Design | Development | Testing | Go-live | Dev Ops.

Achievements & Publications

Memory Leaks in JavaScript - Speaker at India's first official jQuery Conf, 2015

Devmate - An open source ruby library with 4000+ downloads

Rudimentor - A web app for drummers to track their rudiments

Gitanjali - Most downloaded Android app for the Nobel prize winning poem 'Gitanjali' by Tagore

Auto Deployer - Shell script utility to automate Message Broker deployments, published in iRAM, IBM

Innovation Team Award, Eminence and Excellence Award - Awarded by the client Vodafone